uh thank you everyone it's uh a
privilege to be part of uh nff
2023 uh a wonderful audience and this is
a very opportune moment it's uh a great
collaboration that uh that we are going
to talk about today uh for the first
time we've collaborated with the ICI
Lombard to take a look at what is the U
you know status of insurance in India as
we explore uh evolution of insurance as
a sector with digitalization with
emerging Technologies how do we look at
using Technologies to further the
penetration of insurance and what better
than to assess and analyze uh the
shaping Trends and the future of the
market with the market leader uh IC
Lombard so please uh um on everybody's
behalf I would like to extend a warm
welcome to Mr Gish nyak thank you uh CTO
Health uh and claims at uh IC Lombard
General Insurance uh Corporation limited
uh Mr Girish thank you for giving us the
time and the opportunity to connect with
you and understand more uh uh Mr n um
you know when we did this report
together what we've explored our Trends
uh about the insurance Market globally
uh we've seen the global market to be
very very volatile in the last few years
uh especially because of the pandemic um
life and non-life both uh but when we
started exploring the non-life part uh
it's an interesting Trend that not just
the pandemic but generally people are uh
you know consumers are moving towards
more non-life Insurance like health and
motor uh those are becoming more
important uh because life is now almost
mainstream table Stakes right uh so
definitely there's a lot more momentum
in that area uh and as uh the market
leader you would have definitely
observed that more so after the co when
digitalization picked up so uh what
would be interesting uh Mr nyak to begin
with is an understanding of how has the
preco versus the postco uh scenario been
in the non-life insurance sector in
India we know India is just about 1%
penetrated when it comes to non-life
insurance but there's been a lot more
momentum when we talk about health we
are beginning to talk more about not
just Curative or illness related covers
which are standard but more preventive
wellness-based uh awareness um you know
and insurance sector is responding to
those kinds of changes what's been your
experience when you see the preo versus
the postco
momentum I think uh one of the biggest
changes that has really happened uh from
pre-o to postco is the change in the
complexion of the uh non-life uh or for
use of better ter General Insurance
Market as we uh Know It uh prior to co
motor was the largest segment and motor
has been the largest segment for a lot
of years uh Health was growing but uh
motor really was where uh the large
amount of businesses should be
concentrated last two years Health has
really taken uh Center Stage it is now
the largest segment uh that you have
it's overtaken motor so that's a big big
change that has happened postco in terms
of how the
uh uh General Insurance Market has uh
things the other is uh as we see
digitalization right and uh we talk
about uh the entire ecosystem which is
going more digital and a lot of changes
happened in the last uh four to five
years in the entire uh ecosystem we had
uh the entire UPI Revolution we have had
uh the mobile and data Revolution where
we are the largest consumers of uh data
so it's really made uh the Common Man
very familiar with digital payments I
mean a person who earlier you wouldn't
expect to go through an uh mobile app or
uh internet e-commerce site and complete
a transaction into end is today very
comfortable whipping out his phone or
and scanning a QR code and making
digital payments right that's that's a
change that is taking place and if you
look at uh how the U consumer Behavior
also has changed if you look at today's
uh uh New Age consumer she's very happy
making digital payments very happy
consuming content OT content on the
mobile uh ordering food through digital
apps so and all these Journeys have been
made very focused on customer uh uh
needs and they're available to the
customer where uh it's required when
it's required now U and if you just look
at how what and what happens when this
same customer wants to purchase
insurance uh digitally uh the story
doesn't appear so be so too bright right
uh a most of products which are uh the
traditional Insurance products are very
difficult to sell online so if you want
to buy health insurance online uh very
few of you will be able to go through a
completely digital Journey you will need
uh at least a human calling you uh
through a call center to kind of uh
complete that process uh the policy
issuance process also is pretty
cumbersome in terms of the steps it
takes you through so it's it's there's a
lot of catchup that the insurance
industry really has to do when it when
we talk of digitization and making those
customer Journeys for uh consumers
seamless enough to really have digital
Insurance take off
significantly makes sense and I think
you touched upon a very interesting uh
point that we explore in the study we've
done a survey of about 2,000 retail
consumers people like you and I right we
went to tier 2 tier 1 tier 2 tier three
cities across age groups gender
education employment income levels uh uh
and we've looked at multiple kinds of
categorizations to see what is really
making people a come and buy insurance
and stick with their insurance purchases
over a longer period of time two do that
digitally uh the process and three how
well um you know satisfied or how highly
satisfied are they with their digital
journey and this is where the report
throws out something very very
interesting which is one as Mr nyak
pointed out that uh getting people to
the point of buying thinking about
insurance and buying Insurance that's
been tough uh no two ways about it and
there's a lot more work to be done but
the moment a digital option comes in
front of them and that to what we've
seen seen is that traditional carriers
do have an advantage there through their
websites and apps uh contrary to popular
belief that uh you know you would want
the new age platforms only it's not so
much people are using New Age platforms
to search compare but at the end of the
day they are coming back to traditionals
uh insurers to buy it from their digital
formats um and that is very interesting
because that offers the combination of
technology and Market reach or access
that incumbents have and when that
digital buying or digital Insurance
procurement is uh is is happening the
level of satisfaction repeatability
retention goes up significantly we've
seen those numbers in the late '70s
early 8s and that's very encouraging so
uh uh Mr n great Point what will it take
for uh the insurance ecosystem to make
this digital transformation happen
quickly and take it to the customers I
think the three things that we are
beginning to see that will work here is
one customer awareness two making the
custo making digital channels accessible
to the customers and three making
insurance on the digital channel
affordable for the consumers so your
thoughts on how uh icsa Lombard is
approaching this and how do you think
the overall Insurance ecosystem should
be approaching
this yeah uh great points I mean uh you
made out there uh or three things which
are required to kind of push digital I
think what uh we do see is that uh when
you try and sell traditional Insurance
products online
uh some as industry we've never really
been able to break down our products and
make them simple for uh consumers and
that's our our bad it's it's it's
something that we need to get right but
what uh we have kind of tried and uh
done for uh getting digital
uh Journeys ago is tried and uh try and
look at embedded insurance and when I
say embedded insurance I mean
uh the customer is traversing a digital
Journey on a partner
website you offer appropriate protection
at a point in time uh in that Journey
you don't bring them back to the uh
insurance carriers website you just have
the uh entire purchase experience
completely embedded in that uh Native
Journey and that has worked for us uh we
have uh close to 100 Partners uh that we
work with uh a lot of finex uh
uh a lot of lending apps so we we do
work with uh many of them and we have uh
a lot of embedded products which we and
they are again because of nature of
product they're very small ticket size
products they can't be uh large but the
volume of them these products is
significant in terms of number of uh
transactions done so that's that's one
part of the uh story the other is also
trying to design products which are uh
taking care of risks which uh earlier
were not taken care of for example cyber
risk that's something that no product
does take care of today and it's a
very uh felt need in the market because
there are people who are losing money to
online fraud and you need some way to
cover that and is the industry able to
design a product which can
uh cater to those needs so those are
some of the new uh ways in which you can
kind kind of try and and those are
products which are going to formed today
and they will be completely digital
online it and they need not be as
complex as the products that we have uh
existing so those are uh some of the
changes that you see uh in the insurance
way insurance is sold digitally and
online as we uh go
ahead very interesting uh uh and I think
to certain extent you allude Ed to the
point that that also would require
probably the carriers to manage their
core systems very differently uh the way
claims underwriting risks analytics Etc
Works uh probably a lot more technology
infusion uh so would love to understand
from your perspective as you see this
Market you know 1% uh what would and
maybe I'm just throwing out a hypothesis
you know if we were to get to 5% more
than that right uh what New Age
Technologies do you see will make this
happen one and what kind of Partnerships
we see a lot more um you know
Investments coming into the insurex and
very very encouraging Partnerships
between the large guys and the insex the
startups uh both the provider side the
aggregator side uh and this partnership
seems to be working very well for a
large market like India where do you see
technology actually uh playing a part
here more Partnerships or do you see
more consolidation do you see some very
very Cutting Edge um you know Tech work
being taken up by insurers to make sure
that the reaches uh is is appropriate
your thoughts on what's going to unravel
in the next 3 to 5
years so uh like said we we actually
consider ourselves as a tech company
with sales insurance so uh and we need
to consider look at ourselves that way
because uh that's where we're facing
competition from is the New Age digital
uh insex and fintex right uh so we went
we completely migrated to Cloud uh a
couple of years back uh with the first
large uh Legacy Insurance player to do
that we are completely on the cloud so
that has given us a huge amount of
advantage in terms of nimbleness uh
efficiency and uh uh ability to do
something new in a very very fast way uh
you very rightly pointed out uh we need
to reconfigure the core and that's
something that we are doing doing uh
we're in the process of doing that's a
very important piece because uh
traditionally core systems are the ones
where uh change is the most difficult
and that's some and as long as the core
becomes the bottleneck you'll never be
able to uh turn out products uh and
services at a more faster rate that the
market requires so that's
uh uh definitely something that uh is uh
a thing that we are doing the uh working
with startups we do work with a lot of
startups again it's always
a make versus buy kind of for this we
there are some things where we would uh
make our own Investments so uh like for
example in aimr Technologies we have uh
50% strong data science team who works
on certain problems we have said that
these are problems that we'll try and
solve ourselves we will not want to
partner with someone outside because uh
a lot of those use uh our data which is
proprietary and we we think that that
that is the advantage that we have uh in
certain other Technologies we are very
happy uh where to partner with startups
and we do that we have uh uh program for
engaging startups we engage with close
to about 100 startups every year we end
up doing uh uh proof of Concepts at
about 25 to 30 and typically in a year
we'll end up actually productizing about
four to five uh startups so we do have a
program program where we do engage
startups again these startups may not
typically be in what you define as the
insure Tech space because uh uh
fortunately unfortunately inure Tech in
India 90% of uh the insure Tech uh uh
Investments and the report even says
that are into uh
distribution uh distribution is
something that is our strength so we
really don't see advantage that we get
by partnering with startup there but uh
very interesting part some very
interesting Partnerships that we have
are with startups who are totally not
related to insurance they are uh in
industrial iot and uh such likes where
they help us manage
risk uh and understand risk Better Price
risk better in our commercial uh
Insurance business so uh a lot of uh
startups we partner but need not
necessarily be under the insure Tech
definition per se makes sense and I
think you kind of uh um you know
answered uh my next question which is
the nature of uh uh Partnerships uh know
globally it's been more distribution so
it kind of started with making customer
experience a lot better uh and that's
when we saw the um you know explosion of
websites and mobile apps then we got to
the distribution part and distribution
still makes about uh you know uh the
majority of the funding globally that
flows into insure teex startups but then
we've seen globally claims funding uh
inure Tech startups that are working
claims risk Etc go up significantly in
the last two to three years and that's
what I think you alluded to that even we
in India are kind of moving to that
which probably also brings in uh you
know the elements of newer models you
you alluded to embedded um you know
probably more micro products U more
personalization into the products based
on the new age or the genzies who are
who are looking for something which is
almost you know lifestyle based life
event based uh pretty much on a daily
basis or a weekly basis as things change
a lot for them so uh you know I know uh
uh we don't have more time but in a in
in a quick minute uh Mr Nik your vision
of in the next 5 years what kind of a
insurance product ecosystem uh will be
or can we expect in
India I think
uh the uh Insurance products definitely
will uh change significantly they'll be
more bite size because today it's a one
large ticket health insurance policy I
don't think that uh Works uh for the new
generation they would want products
which are more customized to their uh
and also uh a significant portion of say
for in health uh today Health covers uh
only the inpatient treatment which is
about 30% of the market 70% of the
Market is outpatient treatment which is
not covered uh by any insurance policy
so a lot of investment in that space on
how to get uh OPD covered it would
include uh not just paying claims at a
time of illness when you get admitted to
hospital but actually working with the
uh insured to on a regular basis uh for
uh maintaining Fitness again used
through use of uh technology like
variables and uh stuff where where you
work with the insured you maintain
Fitness maintain health so that
the uh the illness doesn't happen so
then the claims so it's uh good for the
insurer good for the uh insured as well
so those are outcomes that kind of uh
will be driven by uh the insurance
industry uh very enlighting very in
insightful I know we had a short time
but in the short time I think you if I
were to summarize Insurance backed by
technology is up for major
transformation as we as consumers of
technology which is the length that
we've taken in the report uh with with
in partnership with Lombard uh what is
digital going to create or transform in
terms of uh the insurance buying and
post-purchase uh Journeys for customers
and how do we look to consume insurance
with technology so uh do uh read the
report it'll be up on uh both our webs
sites and it's a free publication uh and
look forward to a lot more technology Le
um you know transformation in the
insurance sector thank you so much uh
for talking to us uh Mr n this was very
insightful
thank